<item>
<title>MAJOR CHANGES (read!)</title>
<mm-dd-yy>04-02-03</mm-dd-yy>
<body>First of all, we're reinstituting the "geographic war" aspect of the game. We will set all characters to BR10 (leaving CR intact). Then, the shuttle timer will change to 15 minutes (instead of one minute) and the "broadcast" warpgates will be changed back to direct-link warpgates and will only connect to a single continent each.

This will slow down the pace of the game initially, but once contact with enemies is made (easy to do on Ishundar, Cyssor, or Esamir), then battles should be fast and furious again.

This is a dramatic shift in gameplay, but it's also a return to our original design so that we can test that gameplay with a greater player load.

It is our belief that this will bring the "war" feeling back into the game. Please give us feedback on this via the beta boards. There will certainly be tweaks and changes to this in the future.

Additionally:

- Equipment terminals are now available in Towers.


Other changes include:

1) Reduced Phoenix lifespan from 8 seconds to 5 seconds resulting in a much shorter range and reduced "scouting" abilities. It also takes slightly longer to reload. This is the first step in the rebalancing of the Phoenix. More to come.

2) Lasher has improved aim, slightly faster refire rate, increased direct hit damage, increased lash damage, and slightly lessened lash radius. There may be further adjustments or readjustments to the Lasher as we watch how it's used.

3) The Striker, Sparrow, Starfire, and Burster will no longer lock onto friendly targets. This should greatly reduce their grief potential...as well as protecting your comrades from you. ;)

4) ESCAPE should now properly close equipment terminal windows more reliably.

5) You can no longer pull up the map screen while in a droppod.

6) You can no longer pull up the map screen while you are already on the respawn interface screen.

7) You can now /broadcast chat (or just use /b) when within a facility's SOI. Using /b will broadcast your message to all friendlies within that SOI. NOTE: /broadcast encompasses the entire Sanctuary right now. We'll watch it to see if that's too much spam on that island. However, this should make it much easier to match up players for squads, as well as preventing the world from seeming so empty to "lone wolf" players. ALSO NOTE: Towers do not have true SOIs, so /broadcast does not function there.

8) Mines and boomers now have a dud explosion effect when destroyed by weaponry.

9) Aggravated damage (such as plasma grenades) will now properly do damage to equipment (terminals, generators, etc.).

10) You can no longer manipulate your inventory while dead.

11) Several GeForce 2 fixes: Water now shows properly. Warpgate dome shader works properly. Empire colors on walls now show up properly. Orange "hit" indicator now visible.

12) Fog now works properly when the skydome is turned off.

13) Added a dropshadow to the "center print" text that appears when important events occur. Makes it easier to read on light backgrounds.

14) If you loot a weapon and use the weapon, the game will no longer crash to desktop.

15) Implant terminals and Certification terminals can now be hacked by a Hacker or Advanced Hacker.

16) ALT+TAB should no longer result in crashes.

</body>
</item>

<=========================================================================>
<item>
<title>This Week's Progress</title>
<mm-dd-yy>03-27-03</mm-dd-yy>
<body>Changes include:

1) Conversion of icons to text on buttons should be complete. 

2) Graphics options are tightened up and should save correctly.

3) Caught and fixed over 20 potential crash situations.

4) Deployables no longer destroy themselves after an SOI switch.

5) Explosions now properly match the radius that will cause you damage. Object explosions changed include the Wraith, Vanguard, Sunderer, Reaver, Prowler, Mosquito, Marauder, Magrider, Lightning, Harasser, Enforcer, Deliverer, Basilisk, Thresher, Spitfire turret, Motion Alarm Sensor and the Wall Turret (Phalanx).

6) Hotkeys no longer get shared/swapped with other passengers when the Galaxy you are in explodes.

7) Tightened COFs on the following vehicle weapons: Deliverer, Harasser, Marauder, Mosquito, Phalanx, Prowler

8) Disabled parent velocity (inertia) from all thrown grenades, allowing you to place them much more accurately on the move.

9) Mines and boomers now have a small, non-damaging explosion when they are destroyed by gunfire.

10) It should be much easier to identify ground targets from air vehicles now. (You'll see enemy and friendly names much easier now.) 

11) If you go Linkdead in a drop pod now, you will appear on the ground where you should have landed when you log back in later (instead of far up in the air).

12) If the driver in your vehicle takes a long time to load the world after using a warpgate, your vehicle will hang in limbo (properly) until he loads the map. This prevents passengers from getting into a strange "I'm here...but the driver isn't" situation.

13) Wall turrets (Phalanx) now has a visual destroyed state.

14) You should see MUCH LESS warping with air vehicles.

15) Galaxy autoland should work properly now. (Autoland happens if a Galaxy pilot quits or goes linkdead while piloting. It takes the Galaxy to a safe landing spot so passengers can get out easily.)

16) There is no longer a minimum bailing height to get out of an air vehicle.

17) Fixed the issue where, if you saved a Favorite with an item still on your mouse cursor, that item would be there everytime you got the Favorite.

18) Motion sensor radii are now accurately reflected on the overhead map. (They were being shown as too small.)

19) secure Trade no longer crashes your client.

20) Sound options now save accurately.

21) ANT NTU meter now accurately updates after using a warpgate.

22) Fixed a bug that let weapons continue to appear to fire after a player's death.

23) Wall turrets now show their muzzle flashes correctly.

24) You can no longer "queue up" keystrokes for doing things like equipping/unequipping weapons or changing ammunition. You have to wait until the animation is done before using that keystroke again. This prevents annoying equip/unequip "stacking".

25) You can no longer deconstruct TO an AMS if you're in MAX armor. You can deconstruct FROM an AMS...but not TO it.

26) You now get a "death fog" after you die. The fog plane slowly rolls in as your auto-release timer expires, letting you see less and less of the world as your capacity to be Revived goes away.

27) Squad member names are now gold...not white. This makes them easier to see in snow situations.

28) Tracers no longer go through walls, objects and geometry.

29) Afterburner sounds should now neatly go away when you stop hitting the button. (They previously sometimes stuck "on".)

30) You should no longer be able to hang your game by bringing up the map screen when using a drop pod.

31) Mouse sensitivity has been changed to make it easier to adjust. If you have manually changed your mouse senstivity, you will probably need to adjust it again now.

32) You should no longer explode if you are driving a Galaxy and it takes a long time to load a continent while using a warpgate.

33) Lancer has been tuned to make it more accurate over distance.

34) Map screen is friendlier to other resolutions now. You can properly close it at resolutions other than 1024x768 now.

35) You should no longer get a misaligned reticule after dying in a vehicle.

36) Mouse cursor now properly goes away when a Locker is closed.

37) The bunkers connected by an underground tunnel had a problem with spherepaks. They now can be correctly fought within and should have no further collision issues.

38) Using a hacked object should now work properly again.

39) Implant terminal now has first-time help again. :)

40) You can now hack Implant terminals, Certification terminals, and Lockers in enemy facilities.

41) You can now actually USE an enemy vehicle terminal after hacking it. Previously, you could hack it, but the terminal would tell you it was owned by the wrong empire still.

42) Motion sensors now properly show names and health.

43) Some rudimentary inside/outside sound occlusion is now in place. This should greatly reduce the sounds you hear when inside a building. This is coarse for now, but will be better soon.

44) You no longer heal to full health upon recalling to sanctuary. 

45) Map text sorts to the top now, making it easier to see over SOIs and hot spots when on the map view.

46) You can no longer broadcast warpgate to enemy sanctuaries. (Oops!)

47) Damage arcs now show up on low-end video cards.

48) Decimator camera mode no longer fires all available shots.

49) Jumping is much easier to control now. Try jumping on crates.

50) MAX armors can no longer bypass the turning restrictions by adjusting their mouse sensitivity.

51) Secondary firing modes now show alternate firemode icon in Reavers, Vanguards and Lightnings.

52) Projectile impacts will now properly show again.

53) You can no longer bail out of a drop pod.

54) Further separated the aiming of a vehicle turret from the driver steering. You should find it MUCH easier to use a vehicle turret now.

</body>
</item>

<=========================================================================>
<item>
<title>Thursday's Megapatch</title>
<mm-dd-yy>03-20-03</mm-dd-yy>
<body>This patch will go "live" today. Changes include:

1)  Sound falloffs have been adjusted on vehicles to give better clues to vehicle location, as well as to provide better audio cues for when certain vehicles are approaching you.

2) Chat pane is now much more translucent unless you mouse-over on it. (Proximity map translucency is coming in next patch.)

3) There is now a crouch indicator on the HUD to let you know when you are crouched.

4) When your Mosquito's overflight ability is active (you are at 50% throttle or less) then you'll get an icon on your HUD letting you know.

5) If your account is logged in already, and you then try to log in from another machine, the logged in connection will be broken, allowing you to login from the other location.

6) You now get "center print" feedback whenever someone is trying to heal you, repair your armor, or repair the vehicle you are driving/piloting.

7) Combat Engineers can now deploy Spitfire turrets and Motion Sensors *anywhere in the world* except in enemy SOIs. (Previously, they were constrained to only within a friendly SOI.) Each engineer has personal limits on how many Spitfires or Motion Sensors they can deploy (just like with Mines).

8) You now get a HUD indicator that flashes whenever you are being detected by any facility radar or motion sensor.

9) You are now able to hack equip terminals, vehicle terminals as well as med and adv. med terminals while a building is either neutral or in a "hacked" state. This makes Hackers much more useful in general.

10) Splash effect graphics now correctly match the actual damage radius of the projectile. This should help you assess whether the splash damage is effective or not. Vehicle explosions, and some aesthetic improvements to the various explosions still are forthcoming.

11) Bolt Driver now has a sniper scope effect. This is applied to all instances of zooming, but only the Bolt Driver gets the crosshair ticks within the circle.

12) Your interface windows should never overlap again...unless you manually choose to move them that way.

13) NC MAX shield now drops when firing for a couple seconds, making the MAX much more vulnerable during this time.

14) Most iconic buttons have been replaced with text buttons to make our interface more useful and understandable.

15) You can now easily move items from your inv grid to either a locker, trunk, or loot box by right-clicking the item to be moved. You can also swap like-sized items in holsters with inventory items if you right-click the item in the inventory grid (*not* the holster).

16) If your squadmate sees an enemy, then that enemy is added to the proximity map radar for ALL squadmembers to see. That enemy disappears from radar as soon as visual contact is lost unless some other means of detecting it (motion sensor or facility radar) still can detect it.

17) Your follow-camera (third-person perspective) is now locked behind your player/vehicle. You can no longer rotate your view around in third-person perspective. Vehicle camera views are probably coming later to compensate for this, but the "quick check my six" for player avatars, with no representation that they were actually watching you, was considered unfair and not fun.

18) You don't see the Respawn Map Interface now until you RELEASE by left-clicking the mouse. Until then, you'll see your corpse and the world around you. After you click to Release, you'll get the standard Respawn map you're used to now.

19) The yellow and red room lights (showing hack state and gen destroyed state) are removed. In their place, we've activated the "trouble lights" in the various rooms to let you know when the facility is hacked or without power. (Cosmetic change.)

20) Turrets should now look destroyed when they are actually destroyed.

21) The coarse drop zone selection has been fixed and you should be able to drop much more precisely now.

</body>
</item>

<=========================================================================>
<item>
<title>Tuesday's Build</title>
<mm-dd-yy>03-18-03</mm-dd-yy>
<body>Changes include:

1)  Changed the way we handle textures on the map interface so that it removes the reduction in framerate after switching between 4-5 continents in a row.

2) Warpgate selection icons improved when using a "broadcast" warpgate.

3) Added square brackets to further accentuate the selection choices on the broadcast warpgates and the respawn interface.

4) You can now right-click items in lockers, trunks, and even holsters, to switch items into an out of your inventory grid. Try it out. Right-click on items and it should be intuitive.

5) Vehicle weapons now correctly show up on the HUD holster area again.

6) Many, many dialogs and windows have had their iconic buttons stripped out in favor of text descriptions for clarity.

7) The MAX purchase timers are in the game now. You won't be able to get a MAX armor for at least five minutes after your first purchase a suit. So use it wisely.

</body>
</item>

<=========================================================================>
<item>
<title>Monday's Build</title>
<mm-dd-yy>03-17-03</mm-dd-yy>
<body>Changes include:

1) You can now hack terminals (if you have Hacking or Advanced Hacking) while a building is either neutral or is in a "hacked" state. In otherwords, the only time you cannot hack a terminal is when the building has no power (no NTUs in the silo or the generator is destroyed). This obviously makes Hackers much more worthwhile once a building gets hacked. NOTE: You cannot hack things like bind tubes, that you normally would not be able to hack, so respawn is still off-line during a hack.

2) Vehicle trunks now have more space in them so you can haul things that aren't necessarily ammo in addition to a full load of ammunition.

3) Pre-reqs for Heavy Buggies, Heavy Tanks, and Sunderer were removed. This allows you to more easily acquire those certifications.4) 

</body>
</item>

<=========================================================================>
<item>
<title>Saturday's Build</title>
<mm-dd-yy>03-14-03</mm-dd-yy>
<body>Changes include:

1) Map view now has names for the continent and sanctuary.

2) Grenades will now impact dynamic objects properly and explode. They will still bounce off non-dynamic objects if the "Three-second Fuse" option is used.

3) You can now see other players throw grenades.

4) Aggravated damage is now correctly working as a specific damage type. (Until now, it had been incorrectly using the "standard" ammo table.)

</body>
</item>

<=========================================================================>

<item>
<title>Emergency Patch</title>
<mm-dd-yy>03-14-03</mm-dd-yy>
<body>Changes include:

1) MAX units now have a delay built in between purchases. Currently, that timer is set to five minutes. If you die before the five-minute timer has expired, then you are unable to purchase MAX armor again until that timer expires.

2) 9mm and energy projectiles have been increased in base damage. This increases their damage at short range but leaves long-range damage about the same (marginal increases only). Thus, combat will be swifter at short range with those weapons. (Other weaponry...shotguns, bolt driver, explosive-based projectiles, etc...have not been changed.)

3) The Gauss rifle had its bonus damage reduced slightly to compensate for the increased base damage because it didn't need to be tougher.

4) Lancer now has a four-shot ammo capacity, improved damage against 'soft' targets and slightly improved accuracy when crouching and standing.

5) MAX armor now shows up on radar when in autorun mode.

6) MAX armor now has a reequipping delay, much like vehicles. Once you acquire a MAX suit, a five-minute timer starts. You cannot acquire another MAX suit (of that particular configuration) for another five minutes after that...even if you die and respawn.

7) Friends lists should be reliable now and will persist.

8) /who is no longer case sensitive. So now, if you're looking for MrMxylptlk, you can find him by just typing /who mrmx and it will return the full name. Other interesting /who commands include:
   - /who teams (shows current balance of teams)
   - /who tr\vs\nc (shows everyone on a certain Empire)

9) Fixed a large memory leak on the server switchboard. This should help server longevity.

10) Gunners in vehicles now (correctly) get damage indicators so they know where to shoot when returning fire.

11) You now get damage indicators when hit by a vehicle while driving a vehicle.

12) Reviving should be much easier. The detection zone around a corpse is enlarged now.

13) Characters now start the game with four certification points instead of two.

14) Agile armor is now a "free" (no sell-back) certification. You get four cert points plus Agile, Standard, and Standard Assault certifications all for free upon character creation now.

15) All basic medical terminals now correctly act like Advanced Medical Terminals (they heal armor also) if your Empire owns a Bio Lab on the continent.

16) Bolt Driver has a much tighter reticule at 8X zoom...but only if your remain perfectly still.

</body>
</item>

<=========================================================================>

<item>
<title>New Auraxis Patch!</title>
<mm-dd-yy>03-11-03</mm-dd-yy>
<body>Today's patch includes the following changes:

1) If you are Command Rank (CR) 2 or above, then you have access to "Directed Voice Macros". This is an easy way to give directed commands to individuals or groups in your squad.

 - Left-click on a squad member to select him exclusively for a voice macro, or use CTRL+left-click to toggle selection of a squadmate (works just like file selection in Explorer)
  - Hit the "V" key to bring up the voice macro menu on the map; select appropriate voice macro in the usual way
  - The voice macro you select will be sent exclusively to the squadmates you selected (even the voice macros that normally only go to nearby players, like "Wave" or "Thanks")
  - You can also send voice macros from the map with no squadmates selected; these will be distributed in the normal way (squad only, squad+local, local only)
  - Squadmate selection has no "mode" like other map options do; if you're not in another mode (such as squad waypoint selection) it will just happen automagically
  - Known bugs:
    + Squadmates you select on the map will remain selected (and VMable) if you promote somebody else to squad leader, and you won't be able to unselect them unless you leave the map
    + No selection box yet (currently working on it)

2) Grenades will now work properly against Implant Terminals and Manned Turrets (they were previously only doing damage through direct hits, not splash damage)

3) Stopped "stacking" reload commands so you don't get stuck in repeated reloads.

4) Medkits have a delay period between uses now. No more chain-healing. :)

5) Convergence on projectiles has been completed for all projectiles. The weapons should feel more accurate now.

6) Optimizations were made on the server to increase the number of players able to be handled on a single continent.

7) Bridges are now visible on the overhead map.

8) Improved handling of air vehicles significantly. Try 'em out. They are much more nimble now in all directions.

9) We use all the respawn locations in a Sanctuary now. (Previously only used one.)

10) The AMS "G to use" situations should all be straightened out now, so you can manually bind, and not auto-deconstruct when tapping "G" in the driver's seat.

11) Mines and Boomers no longer detonate doing full damage when destroyed by gun fire (instead of normal detonation). They just have a small detonation that does no damage.

12) Dual-cycler convergence is working properly now. It wasn't converging properly in the last few builds, making those weapons very underpowered and weak. Fixed now.

13) Seams between cloud tiles on the global map have been fixed.

14) Weapons causing aggravated damage now cause a burning effect and sound on their targets.

15) Sky objects vastly improved.

16) Rocklet gun is changed: Primary fire has improved accuracy and its ROF is slightly reduced. The biggest change is the secondary mode in which there is now a delay after you pull the trigger before "all barrels" are fired.

17) Some certification costs have changed to create better "bang for the buck" balancing between the various certifications. Those changes are:
 
Weapons
=======
Special Assault = 3 (formerly 2)
Heavy Assault = 4 (formerly 3)

Armor
=====
Agile = 0 (formerly 2 -- this makes it a default)
Reinforced = 3 (formerly 2)
AA MAX = 2 (formerly 3)

Support
=======
Engineering = 3 (formerly 2)

Vehicles
========
Deliverer = 3 (formerly 2)
Assault Buggies = 3 (formerly 2)
Lightning = 4 (formerly 3)

18) Gravity has been removed from all non-indirect projectiles. The gravity drop was making players view them as innaccurate and modeling gravity on the gameplay wasn't adding significant gameplay.

19) Dud-fire ranges were eliminated from the following weapons: Decimator, Phoenix, Striker, NCMAX Falcon, TRMAX Pounder.

20) Reduced amount of CEP required to achieve lower command ranks. (Want more folks to have squad waypoints at their beck and call.)

21) Options screens have more refinement and are more stable.

22) Locations of most windows on HUD will be saved between sessions now.

23) The stacking order of most windows have been fixed on the HUD so that the window you want is typically on top. (No more equipment terminal hiding under the proximity map and so forth.)

24) Implants and medkits now add shortcuts to your hotbar automatically. You can then move them to the desired slot thereafter.

25) Voice macro files should play correctly now. (Finalized voices are still being delivered however.)

26) Found a major memory leak...and squashed it. That may not be the last memory leak we find...but it was a big one.

27) Much improved muzzle animations for vehicle weaponry. Check 'em out.

28) Beware the TRMAX Dual-Cycler. :)

</body>
</item>

<=========================================================================>
<item>
<title>Finalizing Weekly Patch</title>
<mm-dd-yy>03-04-03</mm-dd-yy>
<body>A few tweaks today:

1) VS MAX Quasar: The default COF (both station and while walking) have been reduced slightly to improve accuracy. The recoil penalty still balances the weapon in full automatic mode.

2) TR MAX Dual Cycler: Same tweak as the VS MAX Quasar.

3) Hand-Grenade Distance: Reduced the maximum throw range.

4) VR Training has been stabilized. It should work now for large groups of people.

5) All known "AMS Cloak Bubble" issues have been resolved.

6) Changes to starting cert points have not been made yet. Next patch.

7) Options screens have been tightened up significantly. Let us know if you see something not working, please.

8) Help stars no longer appear over vehicles that YOU do not own.

9) Help stars no longer appear over destroyed vehicles.

10) TRMAX weaponry now auto-converges at point blank instead of no closer than 5 meters away. This makes it much more accurate at short ranges.

11) Further Instant Action refinements to make funneling players to a single location more effective.

</body>
</item>

<=========================================================================>

<item>
<title>Press Master Locked</title>
<mm-dd-yy>02-26-03</mm-dd-yy>
<body>All art assets are locked today until Open Beta unless they can be added to a patch without undue size increase. We'll rev the art assets again at Open Beta in March.

Today will be spent making EXE changes to make more of our features fully functional.

<<The following changes affect ONLY Dev Test 2. They are not present on Auraxis until tonight's (Feb 27) playtest.>>

Recent changes:

1) There are keyboard shortcuts on the map interface now.
   - G : Global/Continent View toggle
   - S : SOI on/off
   - Q : Squad indicators on/off
   - R : Resource text on/off
   - T : Text on/off
   - E : Equipment on/off
   - W : Weather on/off
   - Z : Zoom in
   - X : Zoom out

2) If your base has all spawn tubes destroyed, you will now see an icon representing that fact on the overhead map. (This helps explain why you can't respawn at the closest base sometimes...their spawn tubes are destroyed.)

3) Storm front progress and warp gate connection lines are improved.

4) Tire and treads now have splash effects when hitting water.

5) We've added yet more impact feedback when you hit vehicles and players with bullets/beams. Tell us how you like it.

6) Looking for Squad *really* fixed this time. ;)

7) Hotspot Logic has changed and when you use Instant Action now, you should be absolutely guaranteed of finding a fight nearby.

8) The vertical line in the faces is gone...forever, we hope.

9) We've tweaked the walking and running Cone of Fire penalties, which will impact virtually all weapons. Effectively most weapons will be more accurate for the first couple shots (depending on the weapon type and recoil penalty/recovery rate) while walking or running. Before they were fairly inaccurate even before shooting when walking or running.

In addition to that, the following weapons have had their reticule accuracy tightened:

- New Conglomerate Gauss
- Terran Republic Cycler
- Vanu Sovereignty Pulsar

All of the above weapons now have considerably improved reticule states when crouching, standing, walking, and running. This also makes their integrated 4X zoom more effective. Their recoil penalties still need to be taken into account -- so running and firing in full automatic still will make the weapon inaccurate over a short duration.

Crouching will always always offer the most accuracy, as it offers the following:

- Tightest Reticule
- Recoil Recovery Bonus


</body>
</item>
<=========================================================================>

<item>
<title>Dress Rehearsal</title>
<mm-dd-yy>02-26-03</mm-dd-yy>
<body>This is the warm-up build for our delivery of our Press Server master tomorrow night. This is the build we'll use to create the final list of edits necessary to complete the build. So have a critical eye tonight and report all major issues to Dave Georgeson, please.

<<The following changes affect ONLY Dev Test 2. They are not present on Auraxis until Thursday, Feb 27.>>

Recent changes:

1) LOOKING FOR SQUAD is functional. Currently, this feature is a bit buried in the interface (we're moving it out soon), but for now, to use this feature, do the following:
   - Hit "P" to bring up the Organization Info dialog.
   - Click on the third tab (the one with the magnifying glass)
   - Change your setting from "Solo" to "LFS" (looking for squad)
At that point, you'll see a list of all Squad Leaders and potential Squadmates.

This gives you a list of folks that you can send /tells to when forming or joining a squad.

NOTE: This interface is getting a major overhaul in the next couple of days. We understand that it is difficult to use now and it will be vastly better soon. Not only will it be easier to use, but it will also give you much better information soon.

ALSO NOTE: Since /broadcast chat mode is no longer available, you will need to use the LFS feature, along with a Friends list, to easily find other players when in-game. (Don't forget that you can also form Outfits after your form a squad!)

2) Weapon muzzle flashes will stick with the weapons now (they use to disassociate when you strafed).

3) You should no longer see the "phantom muzzle firings" that happened in previous builds.

4) The AMS now has its "umbrella cloak". You can see everyone inside the cloak when you are inside the cloak. You can see everyone outside the cloak when outside the cloak. But you can't see people or vehicles across the barrier.

5) Many compatibility issues for ATI, Matrox and the Geforce2 MX were implemented. 

6) Respawn interface is now clarified to make it easier to see spawn points. (NOTE: You can always toggle back on the items that are toggled off if you need to make tactical decisions.)

7) General improvements to the HUD continue. Mostly done now.

8) Friendly mines now have an IFF indicator on them so you can tell your mines from enemy mines. (If they don't have an IFF indicator, then DO NOT step on them.)

9) There are now health bars over Spitfire Turrets and Motion Sensors (only friendlies see them) so that Engineers know when an item needs repairs.

10) There are sensor coverage discs on the map now for Motion Sensors. This aids Engineers greatly.

11) The Global Map view has been upgraded. Some improvements still to come.

12) Grief system is now changed so that you will never gain grief for damaging passengers in your vehicle OR for causing damage to your own vehicle. There is also a hard cap on the amount of grief you can gain in any given period of time.

13) Shot representation is now much more accurately displayed. Previously, any shots that hit you were accurately displayed, but near misses were calculated on the client. This is all now passed by the server and the attacker and defender alike will see shots land at the same place.

</body>
</item>
<=========================================================================>

<item>
<title>Dev Test 2 Notes</title>
<mm-dd-yy>02-22-03</mm-dd-yy>
<body>Even though today is our first exclusive beta, progress continues to march on for the Dev Test 2 server. Today's Dev Test 2 test will occur from 4pm - 6pm CST.

<<These changes only affect Dev Test 2. They are not present on Auraxis until March 1st.>>

1) The ANT got its new and improved charging and distributing effects (powering up in a warpgate and distributing power to the Silo).

2) The bug where you could drop pod within an SOI is fixed. You should no longer be able to do that.

3) There are "tops" to the Air Tower landing pads now and you can safely land an air vehicle there.

4) Several guns have been redone to help solve clipping issues caused when they are equipped or other anims are played.

5) Reduced the number of default hotspots to ONE in preparation for our smarter algorithm for distributing player population via Instant Action. That one hotspot will always be a facility now...not just a position out in the middle of nowhere.

6) There is no longer an ANT certification. Instead, you automatically get the ability to use an ANT once you get ANY other vehicle certification. This should help the world be a bit less littered by those silly ANTs.

7) 150mm Cannon and Flux Cannon both got muzzle flash improvements.

8) Hossin has been revamped a bunch and one of the bases near a swamp is now completely enveloped by swamp. Oooo! Atmosphere! ;)

9) The "sliding state" animation bug is now fixed. No more sliding!

10) The instances where you SEEMED to be facing someone's back, but they actually were looking at you should be eliminated. There was a bug where the avatar could be looking in a completely different direction than what you saw when approaching him. That's gone now.

11) MAX suits don't have torso twist, so they now (correctly) pivot in place to show them looking in the correct direction.

</body>
</item>
<=========================================================================>

<=========================================================================>

<item>
<title>Download Day!</title>
<mm-dd-yy>02-21-03</mm-dd-yy>
<body>Today is the day 

Some of that progress includes:

<<These changes only affect Dev Test 2. They are not present on Auraxis until March 1st.>>

1) Personal and Squad Waypoints are now in the game. Each player has access to a single personal waypoint. To put it down, open your map interface, click on the Set Waypoint button and the click somewhere on the map. You'll see a waypoint appear at that point. Close the map and you look around. You should see a 3D representation of that waypoint in the distance. Squad Waypoints are only available to Commanders of Rank 1 or above and those options only appear if you are of the correct Command Rank.

2) The ANT got a lot of feedback mechanisms to help with deployment. There are now red "X"s on the deployment circle if the ANT is not in the correct position to deploy properly, there is a gauge on the Driver's HUD now showing the "fill state" of the ANT, and there's a lot more feedback about the various Silo states now also.

3) Manual binds on AMSs now work again. 

4) A fairly significant optimization was made in the ClockObserver code, reducing the number of objects processed from 1500 to 200. The framerate was raised significantly due to that change.

</body>
</item>
<=========================================================================>
<=========================================================================>

<item>
<title>Remastering the Master</title>
<mm-dd-yy>02-20-03</mm-dd-yy>
<body>Today, we're remastering the Press Server/Exclusive Beta master in order to make some clarifications to the map interface (for ease of understanding). Testing that new master will occupy part of our day, but the rest of the team is working on bugs and belated features, as usual.

Some of that progress includes:

<<These changes only affect Dev Test 2. They are not present on Auraxis until March 1st.>>

1) When a wall turret is owned by an enemy Empire, a red "X" will be displayed, instead of a yellow mount circle.

2) You are invulnerable while standing in an AMS tube after respawning, and you also cannot shoot while in that position. Therefore, the only way you can die while standing in that tube is if someone blows up the AMS itself. This gives you a brief respite from the AMS campers.

3) Hot spots, drop zones and respawn points are now animated on the overhead map to make them easier to see. There are also different respawn point animations to easily show you which type of respawn locations are available (AMS, Tower, and Facility). 

4) There is now a map "Legend" that gives you an at-a-glance listing of the various icons used so you can easily learn the map. This Legend is minimizable so you can get it out of the way after learning the icons.

5) The "toggle state" icons now also have english text next to them making it easier for players to understand what the various icons mean. This pane will eventually be able to be minimized down to just the icon list, if desired, to save screen space. (Currently, it cannot be minimized, but that's coming.)

6) If you click the "minimize" buttons on the floating map windows, then the dialog expands upon mouse-over thereafter, but stays in a minimally impacting "small bar" appearance otherwise.

7) Mines and Boomers will now work properly when set at Towers or Bunkers. (Previously, they did no damage when exploding in those locations.)

8) The major HUD revision may hit today's patch. If not today, certainly tomorrow. Looking good!

</body>
</item>
<=========================================================================>
<=========================================================================>

<item>
<title>Continuing the March</title>
<mm-dd-yy>02-19-03</mm-dd-yy>
<body>

These changes only affect Dev Test 2. They are not present on Auraxis.

1) A camera jolt has been added so that passengers and pilots in vehicles can better understand what's hitting their vehicle. The impact shakes are scaled to match the amount of damage being imparted, so if you feel a huge jolt while flying a Mosquito, you should consider leaving since that was probably the first of many missiles hitting you. ;)

2) When throwing grenades, your arms should no longer detach from your body and fly through space.

3) Towers now show an SOI so that you can more easily see who owns what tower on the Map.

4) Warpgates now have large SOIs to prevent drop pod entries, as well as to show ownership changes in Continental Lock situations.

5) A new version of ChatAPI was integrated again. Therefore /tell should work again. (At least until the next ChatAPI drop...)

6) Fixed a "character stuck in the world" issue that prevented characters from logging back on. There may be more of these issues. Please let us know if you experience one of them.

7) There are now maximums on the numbers of mines you can lay on a single continent. You will only be able to lay 20 mines at a single time now. You'll see info on how many mines you have laid in your Status chat pane. If you lay a 21st mine, then the oldest mine you have laid will quietly deconstruct. If you lay 20 mines on one continent, and then go to another continent, you *do* get another complement of 20 mines on that new continent and your old mines are NOT erased. So the limit is 20 mines per person per continent.

</body>
</item>
<=========================================================================>
<=========================================================================>

<item>
<title>Post-Demo Work</title>
<mm-dd-yy>02-18-03</mm-dd-yy>
<body>We locked the Auraxis build last night for the NCSoft/Ubisoft/Press Server/Exclusive Beta events. Now we continue to work on improving the game for the next big patch at the end of this month.

All internal testing from now on will be either on Dev Test 2 (our Windows servers) or the Well of Despair (our new Linux servers).

Auraxis (our original Linux servers) are now exclusively for Press events and Exclusive Beta testing. Do not go there except with express permission/invitation.

Thanks all.

Recent changes in our Windows build for tonight (NOTE: These changes only affect Dev Test 2. They are not present on Auraxis.):

1) The damage feedback that was recently added to hand-held weapon reticules is now applied to vehicles and wall turrets, so you should be able to use those more effectively. More feedback is coming for both of these (impact screen shakes, as well as mini-map updates as you pivot in a vehicle or wall turret).

2) The Well of Despair (framerate bug) is officially dead. There's not many bugs that take up something like 30 man-days of effort in a single day, but this one did.

3) You can now see Grenades when they are thrown by other players.

4) AMS terminals will now reflect the correct Empire-specific colors.

5) All body armors have been tweaked with regard to jumping. This includes the infiltrator suit, standard issue, agile, and reinforced exosuit. Effectively they all jump lower (similar to the past, before something changed that caused them to leap higher). Infiltrator, standard, and agile suits can jump above two stacked sandbags (just clearing it), whereas reinforced can clear a single sandbag height (as well as jump over a railing if need be). So the reinforced is more limited in what it can clear. The delay between jumping has been increased to 3 seconds as well.

Bunny-hopping in combat won't work very well now at all (it was never intended to be a tactic -- again, it just occurred when something changed that caused the soldiers to jump higher).

6) Jackhammer: Reduced to 16 ammo (from 32). Now it has to reload more often. Increased reload rate to 4 seconds (from approximately 3 seconds).

7) Lasher: Reduced to 20 ammo (from 50). Like the Jackhammer, it has to reload more often. Increased reload rate to 4 seconds (from approximately 3 seconds).

8) Mini-Chaingun: Increased reload rate to 4 seconds (from apporximately 3 seconds).

9) Sweeper Shotgun: Reduced to 8 ammo (from 12). Yep, it has to reload more often.

</body>
</item>
<=========================================================================>
<=========================================================================>

<item>
<title>Today's the Day!</title>
<mm-dd-yy>02-12-03</mm-dd-yy>
<body>Today's build is the official build that we're using for the NCSoft and Ubisoft demos (unless QA finds a glaring and fatal flaw somewhere).

Recent changes:

1) Significant balance change: The armor totals for most suits have been UPGRADED so that you will tend to last longer in close-range battle. Those armor changes are described below:

Standard
=======
Increased to 50 (from 25)
Increased direct damage absorption to 4 (from 3)
Increased aggravated absorption to 8 (from 7)
Unchanged splash absorption at 15

Agile
====
Increasted to 75 (from 50)
Increased direct damage absorption to 6 (from 5)
Increased aggravated damage absorption to 10 (from 7)
Unchanged splash absorption at 25

Reinforced
========
Increased to 125 (from 100)
Increased direct damage absorption to 8 (from 7)
Increased aggravated absorption to 12 (from 10)
Unchanged splash absorption at 35

These changes will be most noticable over range and against shotguns.

This won't be a magical 'wow everything is perfect now' -- but it *should* be a noticable improvement overall for longer lasting firefights in general.

2) Reduced the damage against soldiers for the Decimator, Phoenix and Striker missiles to 50 points (down from 100 points). So now they'll do considerably less damage against soldiers.

3) Spitfire Turrets only fire at you now if you are above walking speed. So...if you think you're clever, and not afraid of nearby enemy troops, just take a saunter past the Spitfires. They won't hurt you. Really. ;)

4) Cameras should no longer go inside vehicles when you switch to third person view.

5) Continental Locks are in place and functional now. If you capture all the facilities on a continent, then the warp gates will "flip" to secured state. NOTE: You will *not* see any changes in the color of the warpgate on the locked continent. Only the *opposite* end of a warp link is locked. Therefore, anyone on your newly "locked" continent can use a warp gate to exit that continent, but they can't then turn around and come back. You can see whether a continent is locked by whether or not the warp gate bubble is the color of the Empire.

6) If a Continental Lock is in place, the warp gate bubble (on the locked end) will no longer allow anyone to enter. That means that the warp gate can't be used to resupply ANTs. So you'll have fewer options available to you once continents start getting locked...but we all know that's very difficult, so don't lose too much sleep over it.


</body>
</item>
<=========================================================================>
<=========================================================================>

<item>
<title>Approaching Demo</title>
<mm-dd-yy>02-11-03</mm-dd-yy>
<body>All of our features (except Command Structure) are now in the game...some in rough form, but they are all there. We're continuing to refine the executable at this time, but all the art assets are locked in preparation for next week's demo to NCSoft and Ubisoft.

Recent changes:

1) The entire map section has been reconstructed. Everything should be much easier to use now and pretty self-explanatory once you fool with the toolbars on the map for a bit.

2) Respawning is graphical now. When you die and release, you'll go to a map interface now. Blinking lights on that map are your respawn locations. Floating windows on the map may also show you respawn locations on other continents (the Sanctuary is always there, and you may have a manual bind to a facility on another continent). Click on any of the blinking lights to respawn at that location. Easy as pie.

3) Auto-repair rates have finally been fixed. The "Repair" certification will be MUCH more worthwhile now. Equipment terminals, vehicle terminals, spawn tubes, med terminals, etc can now be blown up. When they are blown up (0% health), they cease to function. They will then auto-repair at a very slow rate, or a Repairman can do the job much faster. The device will not become active again until its health is at least 51%. Sabotage is now an option!

4) The map chat now functions and all keystroke functionality is restored to that interface (so you should be able to hit "M" to close the screen again).

5) The Respawn and Hot Spot indicators are much clearer now and you should be able to use them more intuitively. (Respawn is currently a circle, and Hot Spots are squares. We'll change these when the art assets are unlocked after the NCSoft/Ubisoft demos are complete.)

6) The certification once known as "Repair" is now known as "Engineering". It is also now a pre-requisite for "Combat Engineering". In otherwords, you must buy "Engineering" before you can buy "Combat Engineering". This was done to help reduce the number of folks deploying stuff everywhere, as well as to create more folks with the ability to repair things (by making all CE folks have that ability).

7) The Decimator now has a 10 meter "dud range" and there is a three-second delay between shots. Additionally, it's damage was reduced from 500 points to a "mere" 400. Still a major "ow", but more balanced now that it has three shots available.

8) All Towers are now pre-owned. There will never be a "neutral" Tower in the game now. This was done because a) the towers were useless in a neutral capacity, and b) because it gives more flexibility to the hotspot spawning positions on Day One.

9) There are three default hotspots per continent now. These are set up in areas where there are reasonably close gun towers for respawn locations. If natural hotspots (caused by player fights) occur nearby, then the defaults will become unavailable and players will spawn at the "natural" hotspots instead. If "natural" hotspots cease to exist, the defaults will be used again. Players will be lumped into the hotspots until natural battles occur, so they are mostly a Day One feature, or a "4 in the morning" feature.

</body>
</item>
<=========================================================================>
<=========================================================================>

<item>
<title>Saturday Night's All Right...</title>
<mm-dd-yy>02-07-03</mm-dd-yy>
<body>...for fightin'...

Changes:

1) Instant Action will now give you (correctly) the standard default loadout when you choose that option. Previously, it was porting you to your location pretty much buck naked.

2) The new, improved Decimator no longer can be steered when in "Camera Follow" mode. That was just a bug, not a feature. Gone now.

3) You can no longer deploy an AMS inside a warpgate bubble. This fixes that potential "invulnerable spawn point" exploit.

4) Ground vehicles can now be set to 100% throttle by hitting the "autorun" key (default = "Q"). This was already true of air vehicles and now applies to ground vehicles also.

5) Overhead map now has drop pod functionality that you are used to, but your landing zone can be set at any zoom level.

6) To zoom on the map, either use the buttons in the toolbox on the screen, or use your middle mouse button.

7) Your weapon reticule will now help you get feedback on whether you hit someone else with your projectiles. If you successfully HIT someone, then the reticule will flash briefly, but brightly, to let you know the impact occurred. If you MISS, then the reticule won't change colors at all and will act normally.


</body>
</item>
<=========================================================================>
<=========================================================================>

<item>
<title>Friday Playtest!</title>
<mm-dd-yy>02-07-03</mm-dd-yy>
<body>The good ones are usually on Friday. Here's hoping for the best.

Changes:

1) IMPORTANT! The NTU system has been changed. Here's the details:
  a) Each facility has a max of 1000 NTU in the silos now.
  b) The facilities won't run out of NTU for somewhere around 3.5 hours if left unattended. Double that length if your Empire owns an Amp Station somewhere on the continent (about 7 hours)
  c) Everytime you respawn to a facility, or voluntarily deconstruct AT a facility to go somewhere else, you consume a small amount of NTU from its Silo.
  d) Each Spitfire turret or Motion Sensor within the facility's SOI also consumes a small amount of NTU from the Silo.
  e) Therefore, if a big battle rages around a facility, you probably need to keep it resupplied. Otherwise, it shouldn't be much of an issue except at 4am in the morning.
  
Additionally, we're resetting the servers today to a "Day One" status. That means that all facilities are neutral, except that we have one pre-owned facility on each continent. All Silos are full, and will remain full, until an Empire captures them because neutral facilities don't consume resources.

Therefore, today's test shouldn't have to start with slogging resources from the warpgate. In fact, you'll only need to do that when a big battle rages around a facility.

2) ALL weapons have improved reticule accuracy now. We now auto-converge between the muzzle of the weapon and a raycast from your eye to the target so that bullets go where you point your reticule. You shouldn't be hitting low and to the right anymore.

3) Keymaps could be saved previously, but not loaded. They can now be loaded.

4) More new weapon effects:
  - Sweeper
  - Bolt Driver
  - Decimator
  - Rocklet Launcher
  - Striker
  - Thumper

5) The Thumper grenades were adjusted last night. Plasma now does more damage against infantry and Frag does more damage against vehicles and MAXs.

6) Toned down the VSMAX Quasar so it does slightly less damage in its new Armor Piercing mode.

7)  The Decimator is no longer a one-shot weapon. It's still disposable, but it has three shots in it now. So if you take it, you should find it much more useful now.

8) The new map interface makes its debut. The details are too late-breaking to list in this news article, but you should see improvements in the map interface now, and the respawn interface should appear soon.


</body>
</item>
<=========================================================================>
<=========================================================================>

<item>
<title>Thursday's Build...</title>
<mm-dd-yy>02-06-03</mm-dd-yy>
<body>...is full of grace.

More changes!

1) Weapon balance changes. Get 'em while they're hot:
  - TR MAX weaponry now "auto-converges". Because the TR MAX weapons are mounted one-on-each-arm, they often bracketed their target instead of hitting it when the range was reasonably close. Now, if you put your reticule directly on a target, your guns will auto-calibrate so they fire directly on that target. NOTE: If the target is too close to you, the convergence will NOT function...so be aware of this limitation. This should make the TR MAXs much more efficient...especially the Dual-Cycler.
  - Thumper grenades are being adjusted so they have different damage than normal hand grenades. They are reduced slightly in strength because of their extra range and ROF.
   - The Quasar no longer has a "homing on infantry" mode...mostly because we decided that was lame and not useful. Instead, it now has the typical "standard/AP" ammo configurations.
  - The Striker missile launcher should now function properly. Beware my wrath, Edge. :) (Late breaking note: It turns out that *most* missile launchers were broken. They should now all be fixed.)
  - Punisher bullets do slightly less damage, but recoil is reduced so the weapon is more accurate. It's actually slightly weaker now than the Suppressor (damage per second), but has more flexibility and the alternate fire modes (grenade and rocket) make it potentially more powerful than the Suppressor after all. Additionally, the grenades are now "explode on contact" instead of bouncing all over creation.
  - Mini-chaingun has some seemingly subtle changes that affect it quite a bit. The COF is actually increased (less accurate) so that it's the worst of all heavy rifles...at rest. However, that reticule pretty much does NOT expand while firing now. That means that in close-up fighting, it will be MUCH more accurate than before and that it can no longer be used as a long-range sniping gun as easily (because the COF never gets very small).
  - VSMAX Quasar: Reduced the recoil penalty so that it's more accurate, and thus, more deadly.
  - All weapons that have grenades (Pounder, Thumper, GroundPounder, etc.) have been changed so that their primary fire mode is "Explode on Contact" rather than "Two-second Delay".

2) Mini-map should show all rooms correctly now. You'll also start seeing stairways, generator icons, spawn room icons, etc. to help you find your way around inside the building.

3) Tooltips now have an opaque background so you can read the silly things. :)

4) You should now be able to voluntarily Deconstruct in a bind tube and then respawn at a deployed AMS. This was broken previously, but is now functional.

5) "Nearest Tower" is now a respawn option. So now, you have the following as spawn options:
  - Nearest friendly facility
  - Nearest friendly & deployed AMS
  - Nearest tower
  - Manual bind at a friendly facility
  - Manual bind at a friendly & deployed AMS
  - Sanctuary
NOTE: This will all be much easier to understand when we get the map-version of this interface tomorrow (Friday).

6) Special effects have been improved. Here's a list of what's been touched so far:
  - AMP: better muzzle flash
  - Repeater: better muzzle flash
  - Scatter pistol: Accentuates the "MAG" (magnetic) part of its description by bringing in part of the new Gauss Rifle effect.
  - Cycler: better muzzle flash
  - Gauss Rifle: vastly improved. NC should be happy with this effect.
  - Punisher: better muzzle flash
  - Suppressor: now has a small muzzle flash (intentional since it's supposed to be slightly muffled)
  - Jackhammer: better muzzle flash. Still working on this weapon.
  - Mini-chaingun: much better muzzle flash. Still working on it.
  - All tracers: Improved with better directional indicator (easier to see head from tail on the tracer).
  - More to come. Stay tuned. 

7) Sounds have been improved for the following weapons (some tailoff sounds are missing, but they should still be better):
  - AMP
  - Gauss
  - Mini-chaingun
  - Pulsar
  - Punisher (bullets)
  - Rotarychaingun (vehicle light machine gun)
  - Suppressor
  - TRMAX Dual-Cycler
  - VSMAX Quasar

</body>
</item>
<=========================================================================>
<=========================================================================>

<item>
<title>Today's Progress</title>
<mm-dd-yy>02-05-03</mm-dd-yy>
<body>The Master List gets smaller and smaller:

1) The work on the mesh loading progresses smoothly. You should notice significant loading time increases today, but the memory savings won't appear until the end of the week. However, zoning is much faster NOW.

2) The Amp Station and Tech Plant have modified "basements" now. When you go down there, you'll notice it's all rearranged again. We intend this to be the final layout unless there are serious gameplay issues. Enjoy!

3) We are continuing to tweak weapons balance. We are closely examining the balance between weapons and weaking/stengthening weapons each day during the week until we're satisified with the balance for next week's NCSoft/Ubisoft demo. Recent improvements include:
  - Frag grenades now hurt vehicles worse than infantry and Plasma grenades hurt infantry worse than vehicles (giving them some differentiation in use).
  - The Lancer's damage against infantry was reduced somewhat since it's role is *supposed* to be anti-vehicular.
  - Rocklet Launcher: Increased projectile velocity (40 meters to 50 meters per second) for better accuracy against moving vehicles.
  - TR MAX Pounder: Minimum Detonation Distance: 10 meters. This will help limit its close-range effectiveness (similar to the NC MAX Falcon's close range weakness) as well as protecting the MAX from its own grenades.
  - Cycler: Slightly reduced recoil penalty to make its sheer rate of fire more efficient.
  - Phoenix: Reduced soldier damage (120 pts to 100 pts) and added a Minimum Detonation Distance of 10 meters
  - Striker: Reduced soldier damage (120 pts to 100 pts) so that it's not a one-shot kill on soldiers (since it's *supposed* to be anti-vehicular...not anti-personnel). Added Turn COF penalty to simulate it being a heavy weapon. Added a Minimum Detonation Distance of 10 meters to curtail its ease-of-use indoors.
  - Lasher: Reduced Direct Damage (50 pts to 25 pts), but Increased Lash Damage Percentage to 40% (so lashes still do 10 pts). The net effect is that the weapon will do less damage on impact, but will still be able to "lash" nearby crowds just as effectively as before.

4) The tracer effects have been improved. This was done so that all guns firing bullets have an immediate improvement.

5) The mini-chaingun muzzle flash has been improved. The TR weapons badly needed some love, so we are improving their weapon effects first and then moving to the NC shotguns. After that, we'll be improving the beam effects for VS beam weapons. In this way, we can improve something like 18 out of our 30 weapons all at once. After we've done that, then we'll be focusing on the MAX weaponry for our "big splash" effects.

6) Keymaps and sound options should now persist if you make changes in the Options Screens. Remember that you can now access those Options via the ESCAPE key.

7) Drivers of ANTs can now see the charge status of their ANT via a new gauge on your HUD.

8) The Instant Action ("Request Deployment") option is now available on the ESCAPE menu.

9) First-time help windows now show up for 120 seconds before fading. This is to allow folks time to read the darn things. (NOTE: ESC will still close those windows ahead of time.)

10) Vehicle turrets should now be MUCH easier to use. The updating is much finer now (for better control) and the aiming point is now also correct.

11) You should now (correctly) face OUT of a respawn tube when you first appear there.

12) Previously, if your bind spot was eliminated WHILE you were watching the progress bar in order to respawn, you would end up respawning at the Sanctuary. This no longer occurs. The code now looks for other "nearest" facilities and tries to put you there instead. ONLY if there are NO other locations, will you end up at the Sanctuary.

</body>
</item>
<=========================================================================>
<=========================================================================>

<item>
<title>More Progress</title>
<mm-dd-yy>01-30-03</mm-dd-yy>
<body>More info on new modifications to the build:

1) We now confidently run on 32MB video cards. We haven't done compatibility testing yet, so there may be issues with some cards, but we've even been successful running 16MB video cards (with sky and terrain detail textures turned off). Progress!

2)  The chat window no longer shows the "channel" icons unless you move the mouse directly over that GUI element. This change allows the chat pane to take up less space and thus, there is less clutter on the screen.

3) The ANT's physics model has been changed to feel "heavier" and thus, more stable.

4) Vehicles should no longer bounce when you get within "physics range" of them. The tires had previously been interpenetrating the ground at a distance, and when the physics kicked in, they were being ejected from the terrain, thus causing the bounce you saw. This should be minimized now.

</body>
</item>
<=========================================================================>
<=========================================================================>

<item>
<title>Even More Changes</title>
<mm-dd-yy>01-30-03</mm-dd-yy>
<body>Today's Objective: 

Progress marches on. Here are the most recent changes:

1) You no longer step out of a bind tube with your default favorite. It was determined that the current system of respawning was undermining many of the tactical options in a base by making it useless to destroy (or repair) most of the terminals within the base. Certainly the "Tribes 2" strategy of trying to deny access to equipment terminals was impossible, and since that's proven, high-quality gameplay, we want it back in OUR game.

2) The "Favorites" process is greatly steamlined. If you have *any* Favorites available when accessing an equipment terminal, you will see that pane first. You then just select a favorite and the window autocloses. Thus, the process of getting equipment is as fast as "G" (to open the terminal) and a number key to select the appropriate favorite. No more confirmation dialog. No more having to close the terminal to move away. No more having to select the Favorites tab to get what you want. Vastly improved. Two keystrokes to get a favorite.

3) The "Claim Flag" functionality has all been removed and the new capture experience system is in-place. To get xp for a facility capture you must either be a) one of the folks in the SOI of the building when its hacked, and/or b) at the time of actual capture, you must be a member of a squad that has someone in it that was there when the facility was hacked. This is a very flexible system that rewards pretty much everyone that participates in a battle near a facility when it's captured. It also has no user interface and is thus much less complicated.

4) You shouldn't see those crazy "mount/dismount" anims on steep inclines or when your vehicle is flipped any longer. (No more dismounting into mid-air.) If that situation occurs, the anim will not be played and the character will be teleported to the dismount location after a short progress bar elapses (to compensate for the anim length).

5) We should be seeing the first version of the mini-map today. Warning...it's going to be quite rough...but we need to start testing it so we can refine as we go.

6) A dramatic decrease in latency was made last night when objects are within 50 meters of you. The roundtrip for packets before this change was something like 1000ms. It's now something more on the order of 250ms and it makes movement and hit responsiveness MUCH better. We're stress-testing it for the first time in today's playtest.

7) You now (properly) receive experience for supplying a Silo with NTUs from an ANT. Go, ANT Drivers, Go!

</body>
</item>
<=========================================================================>

<=========================================================================>

<item>
<title>Recent Changes</title>
<mm-dd-yy>01-27-03</mm-dd-yy>
<body>Today's Objective: 

Some recent advances to report in the game:

1) There are now gun towers scattered throughout the maps. These gun towers are easily controlled (no 15-minute timer to expire after hacking) and have gun turrets, lockers and bind tubes. In otherwords, they're strong points on the maps that you can use for either offensive or defensive strategies when attacking/defending facilities. They are also fall back positions for spawning...as long as your Empire controls them.

2) The Global Weather system is up and running. When viewing the global map, you can see weather patterns moving across the world. As you watch a weather system sweep across your position on a continent, you can switch back to first-person view and actually watch the thunderstorm/snowstorm/etc. move into view. Now you can actually plan to "attack under the cover of the oncoming storm" and air units need to be alert to changing weather conditions as visibility can change radically.

3) Our Resources system is in-place now. Each facility requires an NTU Silo to be powered in order to maintain energy in the grid for terminals and such. The Silo drains at a regular rate (it drains more slowly if you own an Amp Station), and if it reaches zero, then all energy to the facility is lost. (Time from full power to zero is still being tweaked.) However, unlike when a generator is destroyed, if a Silo loses all energy, then the facility reverts to Neutrality and must be recaptured (rather than merely resecured).

To power a Silo with a full charge of NTUs, a driver must acquire an Advanced Nannite Transport (ANT) at any vehicle terminal, drive it to a warpgate where it will deploy and charge from the energy in the bubble, and then drive to the Silo that needs recharging. The ANT is then deployed next to the Silo and energy is transferred smoothly.

No certification is required to drive an ANT. Anyone can do it, but ANTs are neither speedy nor super-tough. You *do* gain Battle Experience for resupplying a Silo via the ANT. This xp can be shared by squadmates in the area. ANTs *can* be carried by Galaxies. 

More details on this system later.

4) We used to have an "auto-landing" system where you tapped "L" to either launch or land an air vehicle. Launching was pretty cool, but landing was kind of a pain because when you tapped "L" because the algorithm took over and you couldn't control your rate of descent manually. We've replaced that now with a more maneuverable system. You use "E" to ascend and "C" to descend. To land, you just hit "C" until you get close to the ground. If it's not a safe spot, you'll be warned. If it is a safe stop, you will simply land at that position and can dismount. It's much more graceful now.

5) To make it easier to move around in the world, there are now vehicle pads at all facilities. The Galaxy dropship is still restricted to only the Sanctuary and Dropship Centers, but all "standard" vehicles (vehicles that don't require a pre-req certification to learn to use) are available at all facilities now. If your Empire owns a Tech Plant on a continent, then you can acquire ALL vehicles (except the Galaxy) at ALL facilities on that continent.

</body>
</item>
<=========================================================================>

<item>
<title>Key Bindings</title>
<mm-dd-yy>01-27-03</mm-dd-yy>
<body>A quick breakdown of the primary controls for the game:

W		Forward
S		Back
A		Strafe Left
D		Strafe Right

SPACEBAR	Jump/Heavy Armor abilities/Vehicle afterburners
SHIFT		Walk (default is run)
TAB		Mouse cursor on/off

C		Crouch/Crouchwalk (Descend when in vehicle)
E		Ascend when in vehicle
G		Use Item/Station or Get in/out of Vehicle
ALT+G		Bail out of a moving vehicle
I		Inventory
K		Stealth suit (or Stealth Basilisk) on/off
M		Map On/Off
Q		Autorun on/off (Max throttle when in a vehicle)
R		Reload
T		External view (1st person/3rd person)
X		Change ammunition type (must be available in inventory)
V		Open the Voice Macro menu
Z		Zoom (2x, 4x, 8x, Normal)
=		Screenshot

1		Weapon Slot 1 (first pistol slot)
2		Weapon Slot 2 (first rifle slot)
3		Weapon Slot 3 (second pistol slot)
4		Weapon Slot 4 (second rifle slot)

1-0 (in vehicle)	10% increments of throttle (example: 2 = 20% throttle)

SHIFT+F10	HUD on/off

Enter		Opens the chat window for text entry
/b		Broadcast chat - Entire Empire can hear (this is a temporary feature)
/squad		Send a message to your squad (or click the chat pane squad button)
/outfit		Send a message to your Outfit (or click the chat pane outfit button)
/tell XXXX		Send a private message to player XXXX
BACKSPACE	Reply to a private message from a player

O		Opens the Character Menu (certifications, implants, first-time help missions)
P		Opens the Player Menu (squads, statistics)
</body>
</item>

<=========================================================================>
